SAMEER WASEEM

+92 301-4239116

≥ sameerwaseem01@gmail.com

@sameerwasim

in @sameerwasim

EDUCATION

PUCIT

Lahore BS Computer Science 2017 - 2021

SKILLS

FRONTEND

REACT - REACT NATIVE - NEXTJS -GATSBY - REACT QUERY - REACT REDUX - REACT CONTEXT - SCSS

BACKEND & DATABASES

NODE - EXPRESS - CODEIGNITER -LARAVEL - MONGOOSE - FIREBASE -AMPLIFY - NESTJS - WEBSOCKETS

MYSQL - MONGODB - POSTGRESSQL - FIRESTORE - DYNAMODB - REDIS

CLOUD / DEVOPS

AWS BASIC - AWS BASIC COMPUTE -AWS API GATEWAY - DOCKER - GIT -GITHUB ACTIONS

AUTOMATION / SCRAPPING

SCRAPY - BEAUTIFUL SOUP - CHEERIO - SELENIUM

LANGUAGES

JAVASCRIPT - PHP - PYTHON

PACKAGES

Currency Convertor

currency-exchangeconversion@github|PHP, MYSQL Used to convert any currency as base to any other currency.

SUMMARY

I am a highly skilled Software Engineer with a Bachelor of Computer Science from the University of Punjab. With extensive experience in technologies such as JavaScript, PHP, and Python, I have a proven track record of successfully building web and mobile applications, RESTful APIs, web scraping tools, and web testing tools. I have also been actively involved in contributing to various technical communities since 2018.

WORK EXPERIENCE (3+ YEARS)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

RipeSeed | January 2023 - Present

Building next-gen cloud web and mobile apps using various cloud technologies.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Wellcreator | Feb 2020 - December 2022 (2 years 11 months)

I developed and implemented a variety of web and mobile applications utilizing various technologies. Additionally, I managed a team of junior developers and interns, and was responsible for server deployment and database optimization.

NETWORK ADMIN

Master Comm. | Nov 2019 - Feb 2020 (4 months)

Managed and maintained networking infrastructure, including configuring and troubleshooting network traffic to ensure optimal performance, and established new and maintained existing connections.

PROJECTS

PLAT LAHORE

platlhr.gov.pk | PHP OOP, MySQL, Bootstrap

Punjab Labour Court website to digitalize processes and improve case status visibility for users.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for managing backend operations & database.
- Manages project team.
- Coordinates deployment of project to server and database.

PACKAGES

JazzCash Checkout

jazzcash-checkout@npmjs|

JavaScript

Library to assist in the development of JazzCash for NodeJs

MySQL-RCM

mysql-rcm@npmjs | Express, MySQL Library which automatically create a RESTAPI for your backend

XML Sitemap Generator php-sitemap-generator@github | PHP, XML

Library which is used to convert array of url into XML Sitemap.

PROJECTS

MY AUCTION SHEET

myauctionsheet.com | MySQL, React, Express, Node

Japanese Car Auction Sheet Online Verification Service.

Responsibilities:

- Coded the front-end and back-end of the application.
- Integrated Various Payment Methods (Stripe, PayPal, and PayPak)
- Tested the application to ensure it functions correctly and meets requirements.
- Deployed the application to a live environment, such as a web server.

AUTOONES

autoones.com | MySQL, React, Express, Node

Classified Automotive Web App used to Sell/Buy Used & New Vehicles.

Responsibilities:

- Coded the back-end of the application.
- Designed & Developed the database.
- Integrated Various API's & Payment Methods (Stripe, Google, Facebook)
- Tested the application to ensure it functions correctly and meets requirements.
- Manages project team.
- Deployed the application to a live environment, such as a web server.

LIST NETWORKS

listnetworks.com | Codeigniter 4, MySQL

Multi-Country Business Listing Web App.

Responsibilities:

- Coded the front-end and back-end of the application.
- Designed & Developed the database.
- Integrated Various API's & Payment Methods (Stripe, Google, Facebook)
- Tested the application to ensure it functions correctly and meets requirements.
- Deployed the application to a live environment, such as a web server.

INPKR

inpkr.com | PHP, JavaScript, MySQL

Informative Website to provide information price of different items.

Responsibilities:

- Coded the back-end of the application.
- Designed & Developed the database.
- Deployed the application to a live environment, such as a web server.

CITYBOOK (WEB & APPS)

citybook.pk | MySQL, PHP, React, Node, Express

Pakistan Digital Business Book, Other Multiple Modules.

Responsibilities:

- Coded the back-end of the application.
- Designed & Developed the database.
- Managed the project team.
- Deployed the application to a live environment, such as a web server.